Palestine Statehood Committee "Concerning the campaigns for a Jewish Army; to save the Jewish people of Europe and the establishment of a Hebrew Republic in Palestine" Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- 1981 September Addition, 1939-1942
  - Public Record Office - Foreign Office
    - Document 120. Balfour, John to Ernest Bevin (8 pages), 1945 September 10 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416. Includes letter and 5 page memo on Jewish Affairs in the United States at the termination of the World War.
    - Document 121. Earl of Halifax to Foreign Office (1 page), 1945 September 25 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 122. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 September 25 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 123. F. O. (telegram) to Cairo (2 pages), 1945 September 25 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 124. F.O.L.E.M. (1 page), 1945 September 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45382 8533. Regards illegal Jewish immigration by sea into Palestine.
    - Document 125. Rundall, F. B. A. to A. H. Tandy, Washington (3 pages), 1945 September 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416. Includes 1 note in Hebrew written by S. Merlin and a 2 page letter; first page (page 50) is missing.
    - Document 126. (1 page), 1945 September 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416.
    - Document 127. Young, Mr. to F. O. (1 page), 1945 September 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 128. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (3 pages), 1945 October 3 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 129. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (5 pages) - MISSING, 1945 October 3 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 130. Cabinet decisions on Palestine (3 pages), 1945 October 4 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45382 8533.
    - Document 131. From Earl of Halifax (1 page), 1945 October 4 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416. Regards reports on "Displaced Persons" prepared for President Truman.
    - Document 132. Earl of Halifax to Foreign Office (4 pages), 1945 October 5 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416. Regards Arab League.
    - Document 133. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (4 pages), 1945 October 10 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416. Regards Rabbi Goldmann.
    - Document 134. Note of a meeting re: steps to stop illegal immigration into Palestine from the Mediterranean (1 page), 1945 October 12 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 135. From Grafftey-Smith, Mr., Jedda (3 pages), 1945 October 12 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 136. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (3 pages), 1945 October 12 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416. Regards Rabbi Maurice Perizweig.
    - Document 137. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 October 14 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45400 8416. Regards a free Palestine.
    - Document 138. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 October 18 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 139. From G. H. G (2 pages), 1945 October 19 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45419 8372. Note of interview between the Secretary of State and Dr. Weizmann at the Colonial Office on October 19, 1945.
    - Document 140. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (6 pages), 1945 October 21 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/44539 8462. Regards weekly political summary.
    - Document 141. Foreign Office (telegram) to Cairo (3 pages), 1945 October 22 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45394 8323.
    - Document 142. From Earl of Halifax (2 pages), 1945 October 23 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/44539 8462.
    - Document 143. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (9 pages), 1945 October 24 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45401 8408. Regards American Zionist Emergency Council memorandum presented to the State Department.
    - Document 144. Henderson, J. T. to Norman Brook (1 page), 1945 October 25 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 145. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 October 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 146. Howe, R. to Mr. Dixon (1 page), 1945 October 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45383 8537.
    - Document 147. To Prime Minister (1 page), 1945 October 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 148. F. O. to Washington (1 page), 1945 October 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 149. To Prime Minister (2 pages), 1945 October 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 150. Harris, D. G. to C. W. Baxter (1 page), 1945 October 26 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 151. Earl of Halifax to Foreign Office (2 pages), 1945 October 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 152. F. O. to Washington (2 pages), 1945 October 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 153. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (3 pages), 1945 October 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 154. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 October 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 155. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (3 pages), 1945 October 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45401 8408. Regards Eleanor Roosevelt response to Ibn Saud.
    - Document 156. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 October 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 157. Foreign Office to Washington (1 page), 1945 October 27 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 158. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 October 28 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 159. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 October 28 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 160. From Howe, R. G. (1 page), 1945 October 28 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 161. From Lord Halifax (3 pages), 1945 October 29 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 162. Earl of Halifax to Foreign Office (2 pages), 1945 October 29 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 163. F. O. to Cairo (1 page), 1945 October 29 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 164. F. O. to Cairo (1 page), 1945 October 30 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 165. From Bevin, Ernest (3 pages), 1945 October 30 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 166. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 October 30 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 167. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 October 30 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45401 8408.
    - Document 168. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 October 31 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 169. From Earl of Halifax (1 page), 1945 November 1 (Box 15, Folder 3, Reel U11)
    - Document 170. F. O. to Washington (2 pages), 1945 November 1 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 171. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 1 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 172. From D. O. (1 page), 1945 November 1 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 173. Earl of Halifax to Foreign Office (2 pages), 1945 November 2 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 174. From Bevin, Ernest (2 pages), 1945 November 2 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 175. Bevin, Ernest to F. O. and G. H. Hall (6 pages), 1945 November 2 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45419 8372. Includes 4 attachments: 1. F. O.; 1. (blank); 2. G. H. Hall.
    - Document 176. (1 page), 1945 November 2 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 177. Halifax to Bevin (2 pages), 1945 November 2 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 178. Halifax to F. O. (6 pages), 1945 November 3 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 179. (1 page), 1945 November 3? (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 180. Comments (2 pages), 1945 November 3? (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 181. (1 page), 1945 November 5 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 182. Halifax to Foreign Office (3 pages), 1945 November 6 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 183. Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 6 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 184. Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 6 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 185. Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 6 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 186. Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 7 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 187. Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 7 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 188. Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 7 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 189. Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 7 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 190. F. O. to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 8 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 191. F. O. to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 8 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 192. (telegram) to Prime Minister (2 pages), 1945 November 8 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 193. Foreign Office (telegram) to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 9 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 194. Foreign Office (telegram) to Cairo (1 page), 1945 November 9 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 195. Foreign Office (telegram) to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 9 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 196. C. & C. Middle East to War Office (2 pages), 1945 November 10 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 197. Bowker, Mr., Cairo to F. O. (3 pages), 1945 November 10 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 198. American League for a Free Palestine (3 pages), 1945 November 10? (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/461 75872/14b 4818. Regards principles and objectives.
    - Document 199. From D. O. (telegram) (1 page), 1945 November 12 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 200. D. O. (telegram) to Prime Minister (1 page), 1945 November 12 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 201. From Halifax (1 page), 1945 November 12 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/44539 8462. Regards political situation in the United States.
    - Document 202. C in C Middle East to War Office (2 pages), 1945 November 12 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 203. Lord Killearn, Cairo (telegram) to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 13 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 204. Smertenko, Johan J. to Geo. Hall, Colonial Secretary, London (1 page), 1945 November 13 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/461 75872/14b 4818.
    - Document 205. re: Press conference at the offices of the Jewish Agency for Palestine in London (1 page), 1945 November 14 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 206. G. H. Q. Middle East to Cabinet Offices (2 pages), 1945 November 14 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45385 8543.
    - Document 207. Ettinghausen, W. G., The Jewish Agency for Palestine to Under Secretary of State (1 page), 1945 November 15 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 208. Foreign Office (telegram) to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 15 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 209. From D. O. (telegram) (2 pages), 1945 November 16 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 210. J.S.M., Washington (telegram) to Cabinet Offices (1 page), 1945 November 16 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45384 8543.
    - Document 211. F. O. (telegram) to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 16 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 212. Earl of Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 17 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45402 8428.
    - Document 213. Lord Killearn, Cairo to F. O. (telegram) (1 page), 1945 November 17 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 214. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (telegram) (4 pages), 1945 November 17 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 215. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 17 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 216. Foreign Office (telegram) to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 18 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 217. F. O. to Cairo (1 page), 1945 November 19 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 218. From D. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 19 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45386 8545. Regards situation in Palestine - report by Chiefs of Staff.
    - Document 219. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (telegram) (2 pages), 1945 November 20 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 220. F. O. (telegram) to Washington (3 pages), 1945 November 20 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 221. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 20 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/4540208428. Regards Lessing Rosenwald.
    - Document 222. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (4 pages), 1945 November 21 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45402 8428. Regards convention of ZOA at Atlantic City on November 16.
    - Document 223. Earl of Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 22 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 224. Gates, Sir G. to Sir Alexander Cadogan (1 page), 1945 November 22 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45386 8545.
    - Document 225. Earl of Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 22 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 226. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 22 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 227. Gates, Sir G. to Sir A. Cadogan (1 page), 1945 November 22 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45386 8545. Regards joining Anglo-American Committee of Enquiry.
    - Document 228. Earl of Halifax (1 page), 1945 November 23 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 229. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (3 pages), 1945 November 23 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 230. From Earl of Halifax (1 page), 1945 November 23 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 231. Statement of the American League for a Free Palestine on the Declaration of His Majesty's Government's Policy Regarding Palestine (2 pages), 1945 November 23? (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/461/75872 14/B.
    - Document 232. Earl of Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 23 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 233. From Howe, R. (1 page), 1945 November 23 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45386 8545. Regards Anglo-American Committee of Enquiry into the Jewish Question.
    - Document 234. Earl of Halifax to F. O. (5 pages), 1945 November 23 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 235. F. O. to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 24 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 236. Evans, B. to Eastern Department (1 page), 1945 November 24 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 237. Lord Killearn, Cairo to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 25 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 238. From Baxter (1 page), 1945 November 25 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 239. Bevin, Ernest to Mr. Justive Singleton (2 pages), 1945 November 25 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45387 8549.
    - Document 240. Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 25 (Box 15, Folder 4, Reel U11)
    - Document 241. Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 26 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 242. Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 November 26 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 243. D. O. (45) 14th Meeting (1 page), 1945 November 26 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 244. Note of interview at the Colonial Office (2 pages), 1645 November 26 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45388 8449. Present: Secretary of State, M. Shertok and B. Locker of the Jewish Agency, and Mr. J. M. Martin.
    - Document 245. Record of interview on 26th November between Secretary of State and the Zionist Delegation led by Ex-Senator Gillette (7 pages), 1945 November 26-28 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/461/75872 14-B. 1 or more pages are missing.
    - Document 246. F. O./Howe to A. Cadogan, Washington (2 pages), 1945 November 27 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 247. F. O. to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 27 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 248. From Easterman, Mr., World Jewish Congress (1 page), 1945 November 27 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45396 8344. Regards anti-Jewish riots in Tripoli.
    - Document 249. Halifax (telegram) to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 27 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 250. Henderson, J. N. to Miss E. K. Baker (5 pages), 1945 November 28 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/461 75872 14-B. Regards Gillette.
    - Document 251. F. O. (telegram) to Washington (1 page), 1945 November 28 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 252. Wikeley, T. to Mr. Ettinghausen (1 page), 1945 November 30 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 253. Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 November 30 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 254. Cunningham, Lieutenant General Sir A., Palestine to S. of S., colonies (4 pages), 1945 December 1 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 255.To Howe, R. G. (2 pages), 1945 December 3 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45388 8449.
    - Document 256. Cunningham, Sir A. to S. of S., colonies (4 pages), 1945 December 4 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 257. From Colonial Office (1 page), 1945 December 11 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 258. From Shaw, J. V. W. (1 page), 1945 December 5? (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 260. Lord Killearn, Cairo to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 December 5 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45396 8344.
    - Document 261. Telegram from Higher Crumpsal Hebrew Congregation to Foreign Secretary (1 page), 1945 December 5 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 262. Halifax to J. C. Donnelly (2 pages), 1945 December 6-7 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 263. Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 December 7 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 264. Smith to C. W. Baxter (4 pages), 1945 December 8 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 265. Rundall, F. B. A. to A. H. Tandy, Washington (2 pages), 1945 December 8 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45403 8441.
    - Document 266. Hare, Raymond to C. W. Baxter (3 pages), 1945 December 8 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45389 8454.
    - Document 267. From Washington (2 pages), 1645 December 9 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 268. (1 page), 1945 December 9? (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 269. (1 page), 1945 December 10? (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 270. Halifax to Foreign Office (2 pages), 1945 December 10 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 271. Cunningham, Sir A., Palestine to S. of S., colonies (2 pages), 1945 December 13 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 272. C.-in-C. Middle East to War Office (2 pages), 1945 December 14 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 273. Cunningham, Sir A., Palestine to S. of S., colonies (3 pages), 1945 December 14 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 274. Halifax to F. O. (2 pages), 1945 December 15 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 275. F. O. to Washington (1 page), 1945 December 17 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 276. F. O. to Washington (1 page), 1945 December 17 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 277. Halifax to Foreign Office (2 pages), 1945 December 18 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 278. Halifax to F. O. (1 page), 1945 December 19 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 279. Kerr, Sir A. Clark, Moscow to F. O. (1 page), 1945 December 20 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 280. F. O. to Embassy, Cairo (1 page), 1945 December 20 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 281. F. O. to Washington (2 pages), 1945 December 20 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 282. C. in C. Middle East to War Office (1 page), 1945 December 19 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 283. Halifax to F. O. (4 pages), 1945 December 19 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 284. Smith to C. W. Baxter (5 pages), 1945 December 19 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/45389 8454. Includes attachment: letter from Sir Alan Cunningham to Sir George Gater.
    - Document 285. Leicester & District Trades Council to E. Bevin (1 page), 1945 December 21 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 286. Smertenko, Johan to J. M. Martin (4 pages), 1945 December 21 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: CO 733/461 75872 14-B.
    - Document 287. C. in C., Middle East to War Office (1 page), 1945 December 27 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 288. Cunningham, Sir A., Palestine to S. of S., colonies (2 pages), 1945 December 27 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 289. C. in C., Middle East to War Office (1 page), 1945 December 28 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 290. Cunningham, Sir A., Palestine to S. of S., colonies (3 pages), 1945 December 28 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 291. Howe, R. G. to J. M. Martin (3 pages), 1945 December 28 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 292. C. in C., Middle East to War Office (2 pages), 1945 December 29 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 293. Cunningham, Sir A. to S. of S., colonies (2 pages), 1945 December 29 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 294. Cunningham, Sir A. to S. of S., colonies (3 pages), 1945 December 29 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 295. C. in C., Middle East to War Office (1 page), 1945 December 29 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 296. C. in C., Middle East to War Office (1 page), 1945 December 30 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 297. Cunningham, Sir A. to S. of S., colonies (4 pages), 1945 December 30 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 298. From Colonial Office (3 pages), 1945 December 31 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 299. From D. O. (2 pages), 1946 January 5 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 300. To Bevin, Ernest (2 pages), 1946 January 10 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/52508 XM 06874.
    - Document 301. Halifax to Foreign Office (2 pages), 1946 May 12 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/52569 XM 06658.
    - Document 302. Lord Inverchapel to F. O. (2 pages), 1946 June 24 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 303. Tandy, A. H. to C. W. Baxter (6 pages), 1946 July 1 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 304. Clarke, Ashley to C. W. Baxter (3 pages), 1946 July 2 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 305. Stept, H. N. to Secretary of State (3 pages), 1946 July 13 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 306. Ward, Mr., Rome to F. O. (12 pages), 1946 November 29 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/52571 XM 06658. Regards Johan Smertenko.
    - Document 307. F. O. to New York (7 pages), 1946 November 30 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/52571 XM 06658.
    - Document 308. Magnes, Judah L. to F. O. (4 pages), 1946 December 5 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/52571 XM 06658. Regards letter to Mrs. Eleanor Roosevelt.
    - Document 309. Chancery to Foreign Office (1 page), 1947 January 24 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
      Source number: FO 371/61751 XM 06711.
    - Document 310. Wdowinski, Dr. David to Embassy of Canada (1 page), 1947 February 11 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)
    - Document 311. Chancery to F. O. (1 page), 1947 February 14 (Box 15, Folder 5, Reel U11)